I'm on the documentation page for the Node interface,
أتواجد الآن على صفحة الوثائق الخاصة بواجهة Node،
and we can see down here are the properties.
ويمكننا أن نرى وجود الخصائص بالأسفل.
Let's just scroll down a bit.
دعونا نمرر للأسفل قليلًا.
Here are some of the properties of Node
توجد بعض خصائص واجهة Node
and farther down on the page we can get to the methods.
وأقصى أسفل الصفحة يمكننا أن نعثر على الأساليب.
Let's scroll back up to the properties for just a second.
دعونا نمرر للخلف وصولًا إلى الخصائص لبُرهة.
We can see that every Node has a ".baseURI" property,
يمكننا ملاحظة أن كل واجهة Node تتضمن خاصية "&lrm;.baseURI"،
let's check that out on the body element.
دعونا نتحقق من ذلك في العنصر "body".
Let's open up the console by going to "view", "developer",
لنقوم بفتح وحدة التحكم بالانتقال إلى "view" ومنها نختار "developer"
and then "Javascript console",
ومنها نختار "Javascript console"،
so I can access the body by typing out "document.body".
ومن ثمَّ يمكنني الوصول إلى العنصر "body" من خلال كتابة "document.body".
But actually let's store this in a variable.
ولكن في الواقع دعونا نقوم بتخزين هذا في متغير.
Now on "bodyElement", let's call the ".baseURI",
ولنستدعي الآن خاصية "&lrm;.baseURI" في "bodyElement"،
and we can see that this is the URI of the web page.
ويمكننا رؤية أن هذا هو عنوان URI الخاص بصفحة الويب.
Let's scroll down a bit and get to the Node types here.
دعونا نمرر للأسفل قليلًا ونصل إلى أنواع Node هنا.
So looking at "bodyElement.nodetype," gives us one.
لذلك بالاطلاع على "bodyElement.nodetype"، نحصل على هذا.
This tells us that it is an Element Node.
وذلك يُخبرنا أن هذا هو Element Node.
So every node has the properties and methods listed on this page.
لذا فإن كل واجهة node تتضمن خصائص وأساليب تم سردها في هذه الصفحة.